Andrej Suvoraŭ

+375 29 304 19 99 / suvri4@gmail.com / https://github.com/suVrik

Summary

I have extensive experience in game engine architecture, networking, rendering, multithreading, and gameplay programming. I actively participated in competitive programming contests for several years and have strong knowledge of algorithms and data structures. My education in applied mathematics gave me a deep insight into linear algebra and calculus. I started my professional game development career at Wargaming, the most renowned game development studio in Belarus. Shortly thereafter, my team formed a new studio where we created a cutting edge game engine from scratch and a AAA mobile game to utilize it.

I've been making games since I was 10 years old and developed over a dozen small games in different genres and art styles, targeting various platforms. I was always fascinated by PC and console games, that's why in 2021 I decided to pursue my goal of working in this area.

Experience

Independent Game Developer February 2021 – August 2021

Made a game engine tech demo to gain proficient understanding in common rendering techniques. Designed a simple yet efficient rendering API to abstract away from modern graphics APIs such as Vulkan and DirectX 12 with a frame graph architecture to manage render passes and attachments. Utilized a job system to take advantage of all available processing power. Implemented many rendering techniques: frustum culling, texture streaming, skeletal animation, particle effects, physically based rendering, image-based lighting, Percentage-Closer Soft Shadows, translucent shadows, bloom and more. The source code and a showreel are available on my GitHub profile.

Gameplay Engineer at Press Fire Games May 2018 – February 2021

Involved in the full-cycle production of a multiplayer AAA title. Contributed to development of Blitz Engine and its tools. Worked on performance, memory and network optimizations. Developed a large number of gameplay mechanics for the mobile shooter <u>Battle Prime</u>. Developed a prototype of another unreleased title. Many of my ideas impacted the fundamental development concepts.

Game Engine Developer at Wargaming March 2018 – May 2018

Assisted in developing and bug-fixing of <u>World of Tanks: Blitz</u> game engine. Prototyped gameplay mechanics for an unannounced project.

Freelance Game Developer June 2013 – March 2018

Designed and developed browser, mobile and PC games, created educational games for Vretta.com.

Front-End Engineer at Akavita November 2012 – June 2013

Web development using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

Education

Belarusian State University, Faculty of Applied Mathematics and Computer Science, 2018. Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics.

Awards

3rd place Ludum Dare 34 Worldwide, 1st place Ludum Dare 34 Minsk, 2nd place Global Game Jam 2015 Minsk, 3rd place Ludum Dare 33 Minsk, over 300,000 views on newgrounds.com.